画外音：本片故事既非要谴责战争，也不是内心忏悔
-6
更不是描述一次冒险
-5
对那些面对过死亡的人来说，战争决不仅仅是冒险
-4
我们只是试图描述这样一代人
-3
他们虽然侥幸从炮火中幸存下来
-2
但已被战争所毁灭了
-1
以下是演职员表，需要90秒时间
片名：《西线无战事》
大家都叫他凯特，其实他的全名是斯坦尼斯拉夫·凯特西斯科
He's known as Kat but his full name is StanisIav Katczinsky.
他是我们连队的头儿,他的大鼻子最善于辨别好吃的东西和恶劣的天气
He's the leader of our group with a remarkable nose for good food and dirty weather,
尤其是在没有什么好吃的的时候，用得上他的鼻子
but most of all for food when there's none to be had.
我叫保罗·鲍勃，现在18岁
My name is Paul Baumer.l am 18 years old.
几个月前，我们6个人还是同学
A few months ago,six of us were classmates,
我们的头脑里充斥着各种各样的知识、意识和希望
our heads were stuffed with knowledge,filled with ideals and hopes.
约瑟夫·贝母，他原准备学习神学
Josef Behm, who will study theology.
阿尔伯特·克洛普，他打算研修法律
Albert Kropp, who will study law.
佛理德里希·缪勒，他什么都想涉猎
Friedrich Müller,who will study everything.
佛兰兹·堪布里希，他想成为护林员
Franz Kemmerich,who will be a forester.
皮特·里尔，他只想四处寻欢作乐
Peter Leer,who will travel and make love.
不能不提这位朋友夏登，参战前他是个锁匠
We are with our friends Tjaden, a locksmith before the war.
我们连队中最能吃的人
The biggest eater of the company.
维斯滕思，靠拣煤核为生，是个忠实可靠的人
Haie Westus, who dug peat for a living.A good man to have on your side.
还有德特林，他是个农民，一心想着他的马…
And Detering, a farmer who thinks of nothing but his horses,
…农场和妻子
his farmyard and his wife.
在这100码的距离中，我们已经和法国人激战了几个月
For months we've fought the French for a hundred yards of earth.
他们进攻我们的战壕，我们也进攻他们的
They attack our trench.We attack their trench.
然后为了不吃亏，他们还会再来进攻我们的
Then, to keep the score even,they will attack our trench once again.
(Whistle blows)
(Machine-gun fire)
(Shouting)
(Soldier screams)
你受伤了
(Franz) What are you doing? Wait.
坚持住，一直走
Over here. Here, over here.
(Soldier screams in pain)
别担心，你会好起来的
You'll be OK.
快，拿担架。来了
OK, here we come. Come.
快
Quick.
轻点儿…轻点儿
Easy...easy.
他的腿伤了，他是幸运
It's his leg. He's lucky.
他不会有事的，他会好的
He'll be all right.
画外音：你们是坚强的一代
(Man) You are our Iron Youth.
也必将成为坚强的英雄
lron Youth becomes lron Heroes.
这是我的义务，也是我的光荣
It is my duty. Uh, it is my honour,
来帮助你们为这场伟大的战争做好准备
to prepare you for the part you must play in this great war.
我们的祖国需要具备优秀品质和坚强意志的人
Our homeland has need of men of character and strong will.
我有义务激励你们
It is my duty to prepare your minds
使你们能够更好地磨练你们的身体
so that you will be better able to train your bodies
为皇帝陛下，为了祖国
for your Kaiser, for your Fatherland,
为了上帝
for your God.
祖国寄希望于你们
For upon you rests the fate of the Fatherland
祖国的前途寄托在你们身上，世界的命运掌握在你们手中
and upon the fate of the Fatherland rests the fate of the world.
德意志是飞速进步的国家
Germany is the nation of progress,
她拥有灿烂的文化
the nation of culture...
有发达的科学和丰富的思想
the nation of science,the nation of ideas...
她孕育了贝多芬
the nation of Beethoven,
孕育了希勒，还有歌德
of Schiller, of Goethe...
鲍曼
Baumer.
先生
Sir.
你画的是什么？
What is that?
是一只鸟，先生
A bird, sir.
-是鸟？-是的，先生
- A bird?- Yes, sir.
云雀吗？
A lark?
-是一只云雀。-画得不错
- Yes, sir.- Very good.
它站在窗台上，先生
On the window.
-这条线是…-是窗台，先生
- This line...- The window.
-位置不错。-谢谢先生
- Very exact.- Thank you, sir.
不过你到教室来不是来画画或者作诗的，也不是来做梦的
But you do not come here to draw,to write poems...or to dream.
你说呢?鲍曼？
Do you Baumer?
是的
No.
坐下吧
Sit down.
先生们，你们全部通过了考试
Gentlemen, you have all passed your examinations.
你们都已经毕业了
As you know, you are graduated.
你们的学生生涯就此结束
The time for class is over.
而你们承担义务的日子，刚刚开始
The time for duty has begun.
大家可以走了。赫尔·鲍曼…
You are dismissed. Herr Baumer...
你留一下
You may stay.
(Happy shouting)
你，抽烟吗？
Cigarette?
不，我不抽烟，谢谢你先生
No, thank you, sir.
-啊，你不抽烟？-是的。
Oh, you don't smoke.
-好啊，这个习惯不好
(Coughs) Well, it is not a good habit.
但是光有好习惯不免太单调了
But all good habits,makes a dull person.
英语中有句话…
What do the English say?
-只知道工作使人变得…-变得乏味
- All work and no play makes...- A dull man.
是的，说得好
A dull... Yes, yes, very good.
看来你还是学了些东西啊
So you see, you have learned something here after all.
生活中有时要工作，而有时要娱乐
There is a time for work and there is a time for play.
你现在毕业了，娱乐的时间结束了
You are graduating.The time for play is over.
你是一个理想主义者
You are a dreamer, Baumer.
整天只知道画画啊，写诗啊
You draw little sketches and write little poems.
但是现在是大人了，一个肩负重托的大人
But now you're a man,you have your duties as a man,
你对祖国有义务
your duty to the Fatherland.
你是准备应征入伍呢，还是主动参军呢？
Will you wait to be called up or will you enlist?
不…
Well...
当然了，你是不会辜负祖国的
Of course, you'll respond to your call of duty.
你们都不会的
You will all respond.
整个班将一起前进，为祖国而奉献出一切
The entire class will go as one man to serve the Fatherland.
我知道，我将为你而骄傲的
I know I will be proud of you,Baumer.
(Horse whinnies)
(Yawns)
If you could get enough sleep,it wouldn't be a bad little war.
- If you could get enough food.- If you could get enough women.
Come on, Heinrich, open up, we're hungry.
You know the regulations.You must all be here.
We are here!
Don't lie to me. I've got food for 150 men
and I don't serve until the rest of you get here.
The rest are either in the dressing station or pushing up the daisies!
Well, I've cooked for 150 men.
Ah! So then we'll all have enough.For once!
- You've got bread for 150 men?- Yeah.
- And sausages?- Tobacco?
- Yeah, but...- Good, let's have it!
So let's see, that's enough bread for er...
Double portions!
Is that right? Double!
I can only issue rations to 80 men.
Here's Lieutenant Bertinck.
The beans smell delicious, Sergeant.
Thank you, sir.
It would be nice to see this once in a while at the front.
Eh, Katczinsky?
Yes, sir! That's right, sir.
Eat hearty.
(All) Thank you, sir.
- Come on, belly robber, you heard him.- Yeah, but he didn't say...
Look, you... We are the Second Company.
You are the cook for the Second Company.
You didn't make food for 80 men,you made food for the Second Company.
And we, damn you,we are the Second Company!
Well, it isn't right.
Come on!
Come on, stop cheating.
It's not right. There should be a system.
It's not right. I cook all this food... (Muttering)
Come on, come on! Double!
今天天气很好
Today is wonderfully good.
我们每个人都吃了两份食物，而且还收到了信
Every one of us has eaten for two men and the mail has come.
绿色的小草摇动着，仿佛是一柄长矛
The grasses sway like tall spears.
白色的蝴蝶在柔软的风中飘舞
The white butterflies float on the soft warm wind.
在过去的几天中，我们一再面临死亡的威胁
How often in the Iast few days have we come to the edge of death?
不过不要再想这些了
Let's not even think about it.
还是尽情地享受这个世界吧
Let's just enjoy the world.
一切都是这么清新美好
Everything is new and brave.
红色的罂粟花，美味的食物…
Red poppies, the good food,
…香烟，还有夏日的轻风
cigarettes and the summer breeze.
(Laughter)
(Man) Paul? Paul?
我们去看堪布里希吧
We're going to see Kemmerich.
(Soldier groans)
请问，佛兰兹·堪布里希在哪儿？
Nurse, can you tell me where Franz Kemmerich is?
-他，就在那边。-谢谢
Yes, he's through there.
佛兰兹
Franz.
你感觉怎么样？
(Paul) How are you?
有人偷了我的手表
(Whispers) Someone stole my watch.
-狗东西！-我提醒过你
- Bastards!- I warned you, Franz.
-我知道。-你最好告诉医生
- I know.- (Paul) We'll tell the doctor.
你就要回家啦
You'll be going home soon.
这是真的吗？
(Franz) Do you think?
-是的。-你气色不错，佛兰兹
- Any day.- You look fine, Franz.
我感觉…没什么事
(Franz) I feel... I'm all right.
我的脚，特别的疼
My foot. It's so painful.
我感觉很冷
It's so cold.
这是回家的车票
That pain is your ticket home.
不要紧的，你应该为此感到欣慰才是啊
You should be grateful to that pain.
再过一周，你就能抽上香烟，坐在教堂的前廊里
In a week you'll be smoking cigars on Frau Hammerschmidt's front porch,
和别人在一起谈天说地了
telling big fat lies to Katrine Hammerschmidt.
我们给你带来了烟，还有一块奶酪，还有凯特的祝福
We got you some smokes and a piece of cheese from Kat,
你的梳子在香烟盒里放着呢
and your comb is in the tobacco tin.
请把它们放在床底下
Put them under the bed, please.
藏起来。要知道，有人偷了我的手表
Hide them.You know they stole my watch.
佛兰兹，你打算把这个带回家吗？
Franz, will you be taking these back home with you?
当然了
Why not?
你在家里用不上靴子
Well, you don't really need boots back home.
要不咱们俩交换一下，我用…
We could do a trade. I've got...
不！这是我妈妈给我买的
No! My mother gave me those boots.
-那么，你能借给我穿穿吗？-不
- Maybe you could lend them to me?- No.
你比我们大家都先回家
You'll be home a lot sooner than us.
说得对，你不用等待回家了
That's right, you won't have to wait for leave now.
护士，护士，护士！
Orderly. Orderly!
她从没有来过
They don't come. They never come.
我们帮你去找她
We'll get someone.
-回到家里就一切都不一样了。-回到家里…
- It'll be different when you get home.- When you come back...
-我们还会见面的。-是的。我们明天还会来看你的
- We'll be together.- We'll come tomorrow.
-我们明天再见。-谢谢你们，谢谢你们
- (Paul) I'll come tomorrow.- Thank you. Thank you.
我会好的
(Franz) I'll be back.
一定要帮我找到我的手表
Make sure you get my watch.
好的
We will.
你真以为我不关心佛兰兹
You think I don't care about Franz.
当然关心
Of course I care.
如果我可以挽救他的腿和生命，我会不顾一切去做的。这你明白
If I could save his leg or life, I'd walk over barbed wire. You know that.
但是他要去的地方，不再需要靴子了
But where he's going,he isn't going to need his boots.
他什么都不再需要了
He isn't going to need anything.
但是我的脚很疼，真的很疼
And my boots hurt. They really hurt.
为什么让那些混蛋护士拿走他的靴子
Why should some damn orderly get his boots
而不是给他的朋友呢？
and not one of his friends?
他说得对，保罗
He's right, Paul.
我知道
I know.
非常好，堪布里奇
(Man) Very good, Kemmerich.
Very good, Kemmerich.
他们截断了我的腿
They've amputated my leg.
只能这么做
Could be worse.
你知道吗，拉贝丢了右臂，他比你还倒霉
Wegler lost his right arm,which is very much worse.
也许你就要回家了
Besides, you're going home.
我想不会了
Do you think so?
当然会
Of course.
我想不会了
Do you think so?
你手术会痊愈的
Once you get over the operation.
恐怕不会了
I don't think so.
你不要胡思乱想
Don't talk nonsense.
我以前想当护林员
I wanted to be a forester once.
你会的
You will.
他们…现在做的假肢…
They... They make wonderful...artificial limbs...now.
跟真的一样…放心，你做什么都可以
Attach them right to the muscle.You can do anything.
如果你找到了我的手表，就寄给我
If you find my watch, send it home.
你会住进康复中心的
You'll go to a convalescent home.
或许是哥拉斯堡的那个
Maybe the one in Klosterberg.
你还记得我们过去在那里玩儿吗？
Remember how we used to hike up there?
还有那些罂粟花？
Remember the poplars?
小溪里面全是鱼
The stream full of fish?
佛兰兹，佛兰兹…你恢复之后，我们还要一起爬山呢
Franz, Franz... When I come back,we go up to the mountains again.
你可以教我认识各种树
You can name all the trees for me.
告诉我它们的故事
Tell me all about them.
佛兰兹，一切都不会变的
Franz, nothing will change.
我们会回去的
We'd be together again.
佛兰兹
Franz? Franz.
把…我的靴子…交给…缪勒吧
Give...Müller...my...boots.
大夫！大夫！大夫在哪里？
Doctor? Doctor?Where's the doctor? Doctor!
大夫
Doctor!
大夫在哪里？
Where's the doctor? Doctor?
大夫！堪布里奇要死了
Doctor! Quickly,Franz Kemmerich is dying.
-是哪个人？-36床的，那个截肢的
- Which one is that?- (2nd doctor) Bed 36, amputated leg.
这我怎么知道？我今天都截了5条腿了
How should I know that?I've amputated five legs today.
你去看看吧
You see to it.
从早上5点开始，手术接连不断
One operation after another since five o'clock this morning.
今天已经有16个人死了，他是第17个
Today there have been sixteen deaths,yours will be the seventeenth.
大概，共有20个
There'll probably be twenty altogether.
我们要把他抬走，没有床位了
We'll have to take him away at once.We need the bed.
还有人躺在地上呢
They're lying on the floor outside.
火车拉笛声
(Train whistle blows)
Don't forget, change your socks every day.
- Oh, Mother!
- I won't.
-保罗。-是，堪布里希夫人
- Paul.- Yes, Mrs Kemmerich?
Please, may we speak a minute?
-你要向我保证一件事。-你说吧，什么事？
- I want you to promise me something.- What, Mrs Kemmerich?
-照顾好佛兰兹，照料好他。-放心吧
- Look after Franz.- Of course...
你知道他很尊敬你，你说什么他都会去做的，知道吗？
He looks up to you.He'll do anything you ask, you know?
-知道。-别让他遇到任何危险，你知道他很脆弱的
Make him stay away from danger.You know how reckless he is.
-我保证他会表现非常好的。-谢谢
- I'll make sure he behaves himself.- Thank you.
-放心吧。-上帝保佑你，保罗。再见亲爱的
God bless you, Paul.
玛利亚，玛利亚
(Peter) Maria, Maria.
你要照顾好你弟弟
Look after your brother.
你要照看好小弟弟，多保重，再见，妈妈，再见
I'll see you soon. Take care.Bye-bye, Mother, bye-bye.
再见，爸爸
Take care, Father!
好了，孩子们，该起床了
Right, come on, boys. Wake up!
准备出发。嗨！快醒醒，快起来
Let's go. Hey, wake up there.Come on.
快点儿，快点儿，都快点儿
Come on, come on, Come on!
今天天气不错，快起来
It's beautiful here. Come on.
快点儿，快点儿，准备吃饭了
Let's go. Wake up. Food.
快点儿
Come on.
(Groans)
嗨，凯特，你是从哪里搞到这个的？
Oh, Kat.I don't know how you do it.
你下次跟我一块去，我告诉你该到哪儿找吃的
Next time you come with me,I'll show you how to find food.
要是有一天我走了，你就用得上了
Someday when I'm not here,it'll come in handy.
你走了什么意思？你永远不会走的
What? You'll always be here.
啊，我恐怕不会待得太久
Ah, up here "always" isn't a long time.
不管怎么样，你学会了就不会挨饿
Anyway, you'd better learn so you won't go hungry.
要注意认真跟老师学
You pay attention to the teacher.
(Boys shouting)
他来了，他来了，
(Franz) He's coming. He's coming.
-他要干什么？他说什么了？他怎么说的？
(Boy) What did he want?(2nd boy) Doesn't matter.
他说我们自由了，要参加工作了
承担责任，去参军吧，所有的人都去，都去！
We're free.It is time for work, for duty.You will enlist, the entire class.
-当然了。-你也去啊
(Franz) Of course.(Albert) Behm, you too.
-可他们不会要我的，我失明。-他们会的
- They might not accept me. My eyes.- They will.
今天晚上没事儿，咱们来个一醉方休
But not tonight.Tonight we get drunk.
(All cheer)
我们的目标，是去酒馆
(All chant) Iron Youth. Iron Youth.
出发！
To Max's!
(All sing)
♪ Who'll be the guardians of the Rhine
♪ O Fatherland...
Well, young men. Off to join the army?
Yes, yes!
Well, so am I. I've been called up.
(Laughter)
You, Himmelstoss?
I'm in the reserves.
Himmelstoss is in the reserves.
I'm going on active duty.
Himmelstoss on active duty!
Yes, you fine young gentlemen.This is my uniform, do you understand?
This is my uniform!
You fine young gentlemen!
Your heads stuffed with garbage from books!
- You'll soon be learning other lessons!- (Laughter)
(Shouting enthusiastically)
(All singing)
Almighty God, we give thanks for the food you have set before us.
We trust in you to protect the Kaiser
and the Fatherland
and all our brave soldiers...
and our son, Paul Baumer,
who is soon to serve his Fatherland.
We ask for your proetection for Paul Baumer.
Amen.
The war will be over in a few months.
The Russians are finished,the French are crumbling,
our U-boats are starving England.
The Americans will never fight.
Victory is in our hands.
Oh, I envy you, Paul.
You'll march through Paris,the bands blazing, the banners flying.
I envy you.
♪ Fatherland beloved
♪ Faithful and true
♪ Along the Rhine we'll stand
♪ Watch o'er the Rhine
♪ Defend our Fatherland... ♪
(Singing continues)
♪ We'll be the guardians of the Rhine
♪ O Fatherland beloved
♪ Faithful and true
♪ Along the Rhine we'll stand
♪ Watch o'er the Rhine
- ♪ Defend our Fatherland ♪- (Officer) Halt!
立定！向左看齐！
Left...face.
排成三方阵
Form in three ranks.
排成3列
Three groups.
全体稍息！
At ease.
Gentlemen, you are welcome.
You will be my guests for the next ten weeks.
In those ten weeks, you will become German soldiers.
You will leave here to go to your front line units,
where you will be privileged to serve the Kaiser
and the Fatherland.
Gentlemen, you are welcome.
早上好，年轻有为的先生们。
(Corporal) Good morning,my fine young gentlemen.
我就是西摩尔斯托斯
My name is Himmelstoss.
西摩尔斯托斯下士。我是你们的训练班长
Corporal Himmelstoss.I'm your training officer.
你们会发现我是个很好的老师，知道为什么吗？
You will find I'll be a good teacher.Do you know why?
因为我教的东西你们将永世不忘
Because what I teach you,you will never forget.
永世！
Never.
立——正！
Squad, attention!
稍——息！
Squad, at ease.
立——正！
Attention!
稍——息！
Squad, at ease.
立——正！
Attention!
向右——转！
Right face.
向左——转！
Left face.
向右——转！
Right face.
向前齐步——走！
Forward march.
左……
(Himmelstoss)Left, left, left, left, left.
Left, left, left.
左，左，左。立——正！
Left, left, left. Squad..
向右——转——走！
Right turn...march.
左……前进——
Turn! Left! Left! Left!Left! Left! Squad!
立——正！
Attention!
向右看——齐！
Right face!
向前——看！
Eyes front!
向右——转！
Right face!
齐步——走！
Forward march!
左，左，前进——
(Himmelstoss) Left! Left! Squad!
全体注意
On the double.
跑步——走！
Quick march!
左，左，左。快步前进——
Left, left, left. Squad!
向右——转！
Right turn... March!
左……前进！
Left, left, left, left.Left, left, left, left... Squad!
向右——转！
Right turn... March!
左……
Left, left, left, left, left, left,
left, left, left, left, left, left,
左……预备——卧倒！
left, left, left...Squad! Lie down!
预备——
Ready.
起立！
Stand up!
前进！
Advance.
卧倒！
Lie down.
准备——
Ready...
起立！
Stand up!
前进——
Advance.
卧倒——
Lie down!
准备——
Ready...
起立——
Stand up.
前进！
Advance.
Into the barracks. Inspection in 30 minutes.
Dismiss!
卧倒——
(Himmelstoss) Lie down!
准备——
Ready...
起立——
Stand up!
前进——
Advance.
卧倒——
Lie down!
预备——
Ready...
起立——
Stand up!
前进！
Advance.
卧倒
Lie down!
准备
Ready...
起立
Stand up!
(Sneezes)
开始
Again.
Come on, up, up, up, up.
Come on. Come on.
你
You.
再来一遍！
Again!
鲍曼
Baumer.
再来！
Again.
你胆儿不小，鲍曼
You'll pay for this, Baumer.
上枪再来！
Rifle. Fill your pack.
不不不，下士
No, no, Corporal.
是否应该把眼睛睁大点儿，下士
You must keep your eyes open, Corporal.
(Laughter and singing)
(Sings drunkenly)
(Muffled cries)
(Jeering laughter)
(Soldier mimicking) Attack!
(Muffled gurgles)
卧倒！
Lay down!
(Hysterical laughter)
你们的训练告一段落
(Officer) Your training days are over.
现在你们是战士了，将编入皇家军队
You are soldiers now in the Imperial Army.
要做好准备，为皇帝陛下和祖国而战
Fit and ready to do battle for the Kaiser and the Fatherland.
在前线，你们将会理解在这里学习的
In the front lines you will understand the value and the purpose
价值和目的
of everything you have learned here,
你们的教官训练你们的方法
everything your officers have taught you.
对你们来说有时不近人情
Their ways may have sometimes seemed harsh to you,
但是，你们会感谢他们
but you will thank your fine instructors
在这里教给你们的东西
for the lessons they taught you in this camp.
他们训练你们成为战士
They have taught you to be soldiers.
成为为上帝而战的斗士
To be soldiers in the service of Almighty God,
为了皇帝陛下，为了祖国
the Kaiser and the Fatherland.
向右——转！
(Corporal) Right...face.
向前——走
Forward...march.
齐步——走
(Officer) Forward...march.
(Train whistle blows)
(Officer) Open up.
全体，枪上肩
(Officer) Shoulder weapons.
向右——转
Right face.
上车
Board the train.
(Explosions)
禁止吸烟
(Officer) No smoking.
禁止吸烟！
No smoking.
5班下车，2班跟上
Fifth Company, get down.Hold up.
快，跟上。这边走，保持队形
Second Company.This way. Fall out, two ranks.
现在，你们来了
So... Here you are.
按这儿的习惯是给每个新兵排分配一个老兵
It's the custom to assign one old hand to every new platoon.
你们这个新兵排
You're the new platoon.
由我带队
I'm the old hand.
在新兵营地，那些人灌输了怎样成为新兵的奇谈怪论
In training camp they filled you with fancy information on how to be a soldier.
而这正是我们应该努力忘掉的东西
We're going to work hard to forget all that.
我要教给你们实用的，听我的，孩子
I'll teach you practic...Listen to me, boy.
我要教给你们实战技术
I'll teach you practical things.
比如说如何在前线换裤子
Like how to put your diapers on in the front lines.
如何杀死敌人
And how to kill Frenchies.
不用多久，我就会为你们洗礼的
You won't have long to wait before I baptise you.
我们首先得搞点儿热的东西吃，你们先睡一会儿
First we'll give you some hot food,let you get some sleep,
然后我带你们去巡逻
then I'll take you out on your first patrol...
今天晚上
..tonight.
(Artillery fire and explosions)
Those deep booms,that's the heavy artillery.
They're heading behind us, so don't worry.
They always come in threes,they always fall close together.
You've got five to ten seconds between each round to get where you wanna go.
You can hear them coming a long way off,that's the good thing.
Same with the mortar.
But the thing you gotta listen good for is the "Eeee!"
like a mosquito.
That's the small stuff they call daisy-cutters.
You've only got three seconds before they hit you.
Don't wait for anything!
Up here you've got to learn to trust your animal instinct.
You understand?
So... Don't wait. Move. When you're up this close and you hear something, anything,
hit the ground - fast.
- You understand?- (All) Yes, sir.
(Explosions continue)
听着孩子们，一会儿会有烟花的
All right, boys.There's gonna be some fireworks.
法国人会向你们问好的
Frenchie wants to say hello.
你们一定要紧跟着我
You just stick close to Kat,
我让你们动，你们才能动
and move when I tell you to move.
好了，赶快隐蔽，快，快隐蔽，快点儿
All right, take cover.Get off the road. Quick, quick!
(Explosions)
赶快隐蔽
(Kat) Get down. Off the road.
卧倒，趴下，趴下！
Take cover. Off the road!
(Soldiers scream)
(Whinnying and neighing)
快把伤马打死！
Shoot the wounded horses!
打死它们
Shoot them!
快开枪啊
Shoot them, can't you?
快开枪
Shoot them!
(Whinnying)
嗨！你疯了吗？你会伤着别人的
Hey! You crazy?You want to kill somebody?
卧倒
Get down.
(Whinnying)
(Screaming and gunfire)
为什么？它们做了什么？它们是无辜的
Why? What have they done?They haven't done anything.
不该用这些马，更不该杀了它们
Using horses is wrong.It's wrong killing horses.
好了孩子们，法国人不再纠缠了
(Kat) All right, boys.Frenchie's finished with you.
我们走，孩子们，快点儿
Come on, let's go, boys.
快起来
Get up.
起来，我们走，孩子
Up. Come on, boys.
大家都没事吧？
Everybody here?
嗯？大声回答
Huh? Link up, boys.
这只是让你们尝个鲜儿，将来你们会习惯的
(Kat) That's just a taste of the real thing.You'll get used to it.
排好队
You ready?
走吧
All right.
听着，你们现在基本上是士兵了
Well, you're almost getting to be soldiers now.
紧跟着我凯特就会安全的
You stick with Kat and you'll be all right.
(Distant explosions)
画外音：我们来前线已经1年了，我们都是士兵了
We have been at the front for a year.We are soldiers now.
对此地十分熟悉
We know this place well.
如同在家一样
We are at home.
只是堪布里奇死了。我们不断得到关于
Only Kemmerich is dead but we keep hearing about
同班同学的消息，阵亡或者受伤
others in our classdead, wounded.
我们每一个人都经常面临这样的情况
AIways, over every one of us,hangs the element of chance.
如果炮弹飞来，我们只有蹲下来
lf a shot comes,all we can do is duck,
因为我们无法预见炮弹落在哪里
because we can never know where it will fall.
(Explosions)
我可能在拆除炮弹引信时被炸成碎片
l can be smashed to bits in a bomb-proof dugout,
也可能在开阔地带存活10个小时而毫发无损
or l can survive ten hours unscathed out in the open.
当然每个士兵都相信机遇，相信运气
Of course, every soldier believes in chance and trusts his luck.
但没有谁可以永远这么走运
But no soldier outlives a thousand chances.
Flamethrowers. A new invention.
To the list of ways by which the keenest minds in the world
are making it easy to kill one another,
add this miracle of modern industriaI ingenuity.
lncineration.
这里的老鼠尤其令人厌恶，它们吃得那么肥
The rats here are particularly repulsive.They are so fat.
我们叫它食人鼠
We call them corpse rats.
它们长着一副可怕的面孔。即使在空腹的时候
They have shocking evil faces and even on our empty stomachs,
看到它们长而无毛的尾巴，仍然让人作呕
it is nauseating to see their long naked tails.
诱饵是一块发了霉的甚至我们都不吃的面包
The bait is bread, which is so rotten that even we won't eat it.
这些老鼠十分胆大，只要有一小堆面包渣
These rats are so brazen.lf we make a pile of rotten crusts,
它们就会钻出来，想把面包渣拖走
they'll come right among us to snatch them away.
(Excited shouting)
这是一种消磨时间的方法
lt's a way to pass the time.
防毒面具，戴防毒面具
Gas gas! Gas gas!
毒气是最令人生畏的最可憎的武器
Gas, the most feared,the most obscene weapon of all.
我们忘不了医院中的可怕场面
We remember the awful sights in the hospitaI.
一群中毒气的人，他们剧烈地咳嗽
The gas patients who, suffocating,
把灼伤的肺，一块一块地吐了出来
cough up their burnt lungs in clots.
最好尽量待在开阔的地方
Better to take your chances in the open
不要停留在空而低的地方，那里往往聚集着毒气
rather than stay in the hollows where the vapours settle.
(Whistling shells and explosions)
新兵的价值远不及他们带来的麻烦多
The new recruits give us more trouble than they are worth.
每死5到10个新兵才死1个老兵
Between five and ten of them get kiIIed to every oId hand.
他们的死仅仅是因为缺乏经验
And they get kiIIed simpIy because they are so inexperienced.
他们一无所知，像苍蝇一样的死去
They know nothing,so they die like flies.
不，不！
(All) No, don't! No!
(Paul) Get him.
(Heavy coughing)
把枪给我，把枪给我
Hand me a rifle. Hand me a rifle.
等等，凯特
Kat, wait!
他是孩子
A baby.
他还是个孩子
Just a baby.
Mind the wire.
我们前来报到
They're in position.
很好
- Nearby?- Yes, sir.
画外音：我们打了多久了？
How long has it been?
几个星期？几个月？几年？
Weeks, months, years?
其实只是几天
Only days.
昨天我们受到攻击，今天可以休息了
Yesterday we were under fire.Today we can rest.
明天则又要走进战壕
Tomorrow we go up to the trenches again.
(Honking)
孩子们，过来孩子们
Boys, boys, come here.
听着，你们从那边儿抄过去
Look, you fellas go on that side.
咱们走这边儿，快
Over here. This way.
轻点儿
(Kat) Easy, easy.
拦住它，那边儿
Get around, get around up there.
-别让它跑了！-抓住它
- Come on!- Get it!
把它抓住
Get him!
(Laughter)
有人吃肝吗？我可要节食了
Somebody eat the liver. I'm on a diet.
我老婆会加上很多的月桂叶和辣椒粉
My old woman would have used lots of bay leaves, basil, paprika,
再加上一些特别的佐料
and the stuffing would have been something very special.
应有尽有
But all things considered...
丰盛的晚宴，我像个皇帝
(Paul) It was a feast. I feel like a king.
噢，不赖，不赖
(Kat) Ah, not bad, not bad.
我说过，战争也不赖
Like I say, it's not a bad little war.
你从不回答我的问题，约瑟夫
You never answered my question, Josef.
什么问题
What question?
战争结束后你打算做什么？
What'll you do after all this is over?
我们打算酩酊大醉
What we'll all do. Get drunk.
That's the most intelligent answer I've heard yet.
当然要喝醉
Of course he'll get drunk.
然后是回家找妈妈，除了这些…
Then it's back home and mama and all that.
还有呢？
But what else?
跟他说吧，别不好意思
(Paul) Tell him, Josef.Don't be ashamed.
我不是害羞
I'm not ashamed.
他打算去神学院，将来当个牧师
He's going to theology school to be a minister.
在前线待了一年，你还没有改变你的想法？
A year at the front and you haven't changed your mind about that?
上帝还在天堂里吗？
Is God still in his heaven?
这永远不会改变
Nothing ever changes that.
-那么你呢缪勒？
- And you, Müller?- I'm going to be an engineer.
That's all I've ever wanted to be.I'm one of the lucky ones.
- Why?- I've always known what I wanted to do.
Like Behm.
Like the farmer boy. Eh?
Straight back to the harvest, Detering?
Back to my horses and my sheep and the harvest.
And my wife.
What will you do, Tjaden?
Make sure Himmelstoss doesn't get past me.
I know what I want.
We all know what you want.
I want to undress every mademoiselle from here to the Rhine.
We're talking about future careers, Leer.
I fully intend to make a career of my lifelong hobby.
I'm gonna become the world's first professor of lust.
那么你呢？想回去重操旧业吗?啊？
What about you?Back to the cobbler's bench, yeah?
还有孩子
And the children.
有几个孩子？
(Paul) How many you got?
这你别问，鞋匠是个好工作
Don't ask.Good thing I'm a shoemaker,
人不能总买新鞋穿
or I'd go broke just buying shoes.
What about you, Westus?
A feather bed.
Yeah. And a fat girl.
I won't get up for a week!
The question is, what will you do for a living?
Mm?
You know what? I think I'll stay in the army.
- Are you crazy?- Well, in peace time the food's good,
you sleep in a bed and every week you get clean underwear.
In the evenings, you're a free man,you go off to the beer hall.
It's a much better life than digging peat.
Much better.
-来新棺材了。-好像比平时数量多
(Kat) More coffins.(Paul) A bigger load than usual.
要有一场更大的战斗了
That means a bigger offensive.
你看总部的人们想得多周到啊
How considerate they are at headquarters.
他们连装尸体的棺材都运来了
They even send us the stuff to fill them with.
(Officer) Come on, get this one down.
(Officer) Haul them up.
(Officer) Careful, careful.
(Soldiers talking)
你有多大？
How old are you?
16岁
Sixteen.
明年他才刚刚成年
Next year, right out of the cradle.
-这是你刻得血槽？-是的先生
- Did you notch this bayonet?- Yes, sir.
谁教给你的？
Who told you to?
-在新兵营学的…-新兵营？
- At the training camp...- Training camp, eh?
小兄弟，如果敌人用它刺着你，他们不会杀你
Sonny, if the enemy ever caught you with this, they wouldn't kill you,
而是挑出你的眼球，然后在填一些木渣
they'd plump your eyes out and fill them full of sawdust.
现在没人再用刺刀了
Nobody uses these things any more.
交战双方已经达成了协议
It's by mutual agreement,on both sides.
我不知道
(Recruit) I didn't know.
-第一次来前线？-是的先生
- First time at the front?- Yes, sir.
别叫我“先生”，我不是长官
Don't "sir" me. I'm a private.
对不起，我想
Sorry, I thought...
不要想，“听”就够了
Don't think. Just listen.
是！先生
Yes, sir.
你的铁铲好得多
Your spade is better.
用铁铲击打敌人的脖子，他的脑袋就飞了
You hit a man under the chin,you can take his head off.
它还是一根不错的棒子
It's a good club, too.
它很有分量
Cos it's heavy.
要击打脖子和肩膀中间的部分，就在这儿，你能把他劈成两半儿
Hit a man between neck and shoulder.Right here. Split him right in two.
-我的天哪！-这样会干净些
- Mother of God!- It's cleaner.
刺刀会卡在敌人的肋骨里，你还要踢他一脚才能够拔得出来
Bayonet gets stuck in ribs,you have to kick him to pull it out.
当你拔出来，你也死了，哼！
Time it takes, you're a dead man.
明白吗？
Understand?
我说你们的排长呢？嗯?
Now, where is your platoon leader?
西摩尔斯托斯下士说来接我们
Corporal Himmelstoss said he would meet us here.
哦
Ah.
什么下士？
Corporal who?
西摩尔斯托斯
Himmelstoss.
-从奥德堡军营来的？-是的先生
- From Oldenberg training station?- Yes, sir.
真不敢相信
(Friedrich) I don't believe it!
我要报仇啦！
Vengeance is mine!
那头小猪怎么跑到这儿来啦？总不会是自愿上前线的吧？
How did he mess up his playground?He didn't volunteer for the front?
不，先生，他出了点儿麻烦
No, sir. He got into trouble.
他在泥地上对几个新兵做过火了，你知道泥地吧？
Overdid it with a couple of trainees on the muddy field. You know the muddy field?
我知道泥地吗？嗯哼？
Do we know the muddy field?
他太过分了，他差点儿杀了他们
He went too far. He almost killed them.
宪兵发现地方长官的孩子在一旁观看
And he didn't know the son of the local magistrate was watching.
所以他们才会送他来，你会知道他会自作自受的
So they sent him up here. Wouldn't you know he'd spoil it for himself?
他迟早会做过火的
Wouldn't you know he'd go just too far?
嗷，天哪！我等不及啦
Oh, Lord. I can hardly wait.
啊哦，看呐，是谁来啦？
Oh, well. Look who's here.
让一下
Out of the way!
好啊，又见面了
Well, we meet again.
克洛普是吗？你还记得我吗？西摩尔斯托斯下士
Kropp, isn't it? You remember me,Corporal Himmelstoss.
缪勒，你也在这儿？哦，你给我的印象很深呐
Müller, you here too?Oh, yes, I remember you very well.
啊，里尔，贝母，鲍曼
Leer, Behm, Baumer...Baumer.
你们看我的脑子没出问题吧？
Nothing wrong with my memory!
我以前说过，我教的东西你们将永世不忘
Well, I told you that what I taught you,you'd never forget.
看来你们都成功地活下来了
I see you've all managed to stay alive.
除了堪布里希
Not Kemmerich.
堪布里希？不，我不记得这个人
Kemmerich?I don't remember Kemmerich.
你们其他人看来确实学得不错
The rest of you seem to have learned your lessons pretty well.
你要准备学一课了，我上了前线以后
Here's your lesson, Himmelstoss.When you get to the front,
你千万别回头看
don't you turn your back.
你说什么？
What did you say?
你就是大名鼎鼎的西摩尔斯托斯下士？
So this is the great Corporal Himmelstoss?
你是谁？
And who are you?
回答我的问题！小兵
I asked you a question, soldier.
西摩尔斯托斯，路边上有一个厕所
Himmelstoss.There's a latrine down the road.
你还不赶紧去？
Why don't you take a jump?
别忘了我是你们的长官
Do you realise that I'm your superior officer?
你想上军事法庭吗？
Do you want to be court martialled?
注意身体站直了，两腿并拢
Stand up straight, heels together,
长官在对你们说话
when your superior officer speaks to you.
听见没有？
All of you!
立正
Squad, attention!
向右看——齐
Right...face.
向右——转，全体注意，齐步——走
Right turn, forward...march.
左……
Left, left, left, left.
(All chant) Left, left,left, left, left, left.
They are being good to us.They brought us delicious edamer cheese.
We eat and drink of course but there is no joy in it
because they always feed us like this before they send us into hell.
Kat has lost his fun.
When he smells cheese he also smells trouble
and of course it comes.
别紧张，孩子，别紧张
(Kat) Easy, boy, easy.It'll be all right.
你知道，他怎么被炸飞的吗？嘭！就这样
Ah, you see the way he blows up?Boom, like that.
(Explosion)
我要杀了法国佬
(Kat) Want to kill Frenchmen?
当你干完之后，我要用他的黄油擦我的靴子
Hey, give me the tin when you finish.I can use the fat to polish my boots.
(Manic humming)
一会儿就好了，孩子
You'll be all right, boy.
你会习惯的
You'll get used to it.
发起进攻之前他们总是要炮火轰炸
They always shell us like this before a big offensive.
目的是削弱我们的力量，不让我们休息
To soften us up so we can't sleep.
哦，等他们发起进攻的时候
Huh, then when they attack,
我们便无法抵抗，因为太疲惫了
we won't be able to fight back because we're too tired.
已经两天两夜了，还有多久？
Two days and nights. How much longer?
没多久了，没多久了
Not too long, not too long.
他们怎么不睡觉啊？
Why don't they stop?
(Shells whistling and explosions)
你要到哪儿去？
Where are you going?
我马上…马上回来
I'll be back...in a minute.
好了，别紧张，再等等，马上就结束了，坐下
No, just relax. Wait. It'll be over soon.Come on, sit down and relax.
(Shouts warning)
等等！干什么？坐下！
(Young recruit)Let me go. I must get away. I must go!
(Shouting)
嗨！干什么？坐下坐下
Sit down and calm down.
都坐下，马上就没事儿了，别紧张，都冷静点儿
(Kat) Now, go and sit down.Behave yourselves. Be easy, quiet.
控制情绪
Listen...
(Whistle)
Attack!
(Shouting)
全部出击，快快快！快点儿！
(Kat) Come on, let's go.Come on... Come on!
(Manic humming and sobbing)
画外音：我们不能再这样下去坐以待毙
No longer do we lie helpless,awaiting destruction.
我们只能通过毁灭和杀戮来拯救自己报仇雪耻
We can destroy and kiII to save ourselves and to be revenged.
每当我们看到他们的面孔，我们就成了野兽
When we see their faces,we become wild beasts.
成了恶魔和凶手
We turn into thugs and murderers.
只有上帝知道是谁在作祟
lnto God only knows what devils.
即使是你的父亲和法国人一道过来
lf your own father was with them,
你也会毫不犹豫地把炸弹向他投去
you wouldn't hesitate to fling a bomb into him.
冲！冲啊！
- (Whistle)- (Kat) Forward!
(Shouting)
你们在干什么？
What the hell is this?
快跟我一起冲，快上！上！
Come on, let's go. Come on, you all.
快上！还有你
Come on. You too, soldier.
(Mumbles)
快上！你这个胆小鬼，上啊，上啊！
Come on, let's go. Let's go, let's go!Damn it, let's go!
你们两个在干什么？
What's happening down there?
快！
Come on!
(Machin-gun fire)
冲啊！
Charge! Come on!
这样持续了多久？多少天，多少星期，多少个月，多少年？
How Iong is it? Days,and weeks, and months, and years.
进攻，然后反攻，尸体堆成了小山
Attack, counter-attack.And the dead piIe up.
冬去夏来…白天炎热难当，尸体暴露在外面
Winter, summer... The days are hot and the dead lie unburied.
炮弹会埋葬他们的
The shells will bury them.
迎面而来的风带来了血腥的气味
But when the wind blows,it brings the smell of blood,
浓重而略带甜味
which is heavy and sweet.
什么人？
(French soldier shouts)
(Artillery rumbling)
炮弹啸叫声
(Shell whistles)
哨声
(Whistle)
机枪射击声
(Gasps for breath)
机枪连射声
(Rapid gunfire)
(Moaning)
(Groans)
(Shell whistles)
(Moaning)
(Agonised cries)
不，嘘…
No, shh...shh...
嘘…
Shh! Shh!
不，不
No, no...
不，嘘…别害怕，我是来救你的…
- (Cries out)- No, shh. Aider. Je vous...
我想要救你，我要帮助你，抬起头，别害怕
Je vous...help...I want to help you.
Ohh!
(Drawn-out gasp)
我不想杀害你
I didn't want to kill you.
是你跳进这里来，于世无求
But you jumped in here like that.
换了你会怎么做？我想…
What would you have done? It's...
我想我们早就应该这样…像这样…
It's just I'd never met you before...like this...
面对面的
face to face.
我看到了你的步枪
I just saw your rifle...
你的刺刀
your bayonet...
手榴弹
grenades.
如果把这些全扔掉，也许…
If we threw all those away...
我们可以成为兄弟
we could be brothers.
但是有些人不想让我们这样，对吧？
But they never want us to know that, do they?
他们不想让我们知道
They never want us to know.
我们都有母亲
We each have mothers...
有父亲
fathers...
都一样
the same...
总攻及死亡
fear of death.
一样
The same...
痛苦
pain.
都一样
The same...
原谅我
everything.
请你…
Everything.
原谅我，我的好兄弟
Forgive me, comrade.
我会给你的家，写信的
I could write...to your family.
是的
Yes...
是的，我会写的
Yes, I'll write!
杰连德·杜尔，印刷工
"Gerard Duval, compositeur."
我杀死了杰连德·杜尔，一个印刷工
l have killed Gerard Duval the printer.
注意，全体立正
(Commander) Battalion, attention!
持枪致敬
Present arms!
行注目礼
Eyes left!
万岁！万岁！万岁！
(All shout)
我是军团指挥官，皇帝陛下
Battalion Commander, sir.
现在允许我，荣幸地请您检阅
Your Majesty, I have the honour to bring you the salute
第150军团
of the 150th Infantry Battalion.
皇帝陛下，士兵贝纳德
Your Majesty, Soldier Bernard.
皇帝陛下，士兵兰格
Your Majesty, Soldier Langer.
皇帝陛下，下士西摩尔斯托斯
Your Majesty, Corporal Himmelstoss.
全体稍息
Battalion! At ease!
军官们，全体军士们，全体士兵们
Officers, non-commissioned officers,enlisted men.
今天，荣获奖章的人们都为我们
The men who have received decorations this day
伟大的事业做出了巨大的贡献
have all performed actions worthy of our great cause.
今后，希望你们每一个人都能以他们为榜样
Henceforth, Germany expects each of you to follow their example.
你们的皇帝号召你们，从今天开始，充满力量
From this day on, your Kaiser urges you all to aspire to such strength,
勇敢顽强，忠于职守，热爱上帝和祖国
to such bravery, to such obedience to your God and your country.
如果，你们真能做到这一点
If you do, my soldiers,
我相信，你们每一个人都会佩戴上
I am certain that every one of you will one day wear a medal
由皇帝为你们亲自颁发的勋章
pinned on you by your Kaiser.
你们都继承了德意志战士为国尽忠的优良传统
You have all done your duty in the noble tradition of the German warrior.
你们向世界展示了力量
You have shown the world our might.
你们击溃了我们的敌人，他们害怕了
You have stricken our enemies with fear.
上帝保佑我们，你们必将为祖国赢得光辉的胜利
With God's help, you are winning a glorious victory for the Fatherland.
The Kaiser! Just wait till I tell my father.
Oh, yeah? What'll you tell him?
I'll tell him I saw the Kaiser!
Up this close - he's never gonna believe it.
- He seemed like a very nice man.- Yeah, really nice.
Do you think it's true they forced him into this war?
- I wouldn't say that.- Why not?
It's the generals' fault, he had to say yes.
- So the generals started the war?- The French generals, yes.
The French generals told the Kaiser we had to have a war?
No, you don't understand...
Be careful with these uniforms, boys.
They have to be handed down to the next bunch of heroes
that gets reviewed by the Kaiser.
Kat, why do you think we're in this war?
- Protect the Fatherland.- What are the French fighting for?
Protect the Motherland.
And who's right?
Whoever wins.
That's not very patriotic.
- Not very what?- Patriotic.
Maybe not. Maybe it's not very patriotic to use your head.
Maybe the real patriot just goes out and gets his head blown off.
- And gets a medal for it.- Like Himmelstoss?
Can you imagine that little peacock getting a medal?
From the Kaiser?
Be fair, he deserved it.
He behaved like a true German soldier.
He ran ahead when he was told to run ahead
and he ran back when he was told to run back.
The only thing he didn't do like a German soldier...was die.
Do you think that's what we're fighting for?Just to die?
Well, do you know what we're fighting for?
Does anybody know what we're fighting for?
Does the Kaiser?
Maybe if he'd stayed out of it in the first place there'd be no war.
Corporal.
Come in.
Sit down.
Listen, their country insulted ours that's how it started.
"Their country insulted ours"?I don't understand.
A mountain in France insulted a mountain Germany?
Ah, you know what I mean.
- One country offended the other.- Then what am I doing here?
I haven't been offended.
How could I be offended?I've never even been to France before.
In all my life I've only known a handful of Frenchies.
They seemed all right to me.Human, people.
Let me tell you, the only reason we're fighting this war
is because it's useful to somebody.
Hm? But who?
Not for me.
Let me tell you something else about those generals.
They're getting something out of all this too.
What do they get?
Famous!
Hey, anybody ever heard of Vitry-les-Bois?
It's a French pastry!
It's an occupied French village and we're all going there.
- What for?- For seven days' leave!
(All cheer)
(Albert) Ever seen anything as beautiful as that.
Never.
How old would you say she is?
21 , 22.
Oh, no. I don't think she'd be older than us.
I'd say...1 7 at the most.
Oh, she's so clean.
Why not? I bet she take a bath every single day.
Mm, twice. Three times a day.
There's no dirt under those fingernails.
How far do you suppose he could march with shoes like that?
- Do you remember white trousers?- Do I!
I have a pair like that at home.
(Sighs) It would be nice, wouldn't it, Albert?
Maybe we could go over to the de-lousing station.
Why? You'll be covered again in half an hour.
I just feel so dirty.
Hey! Get your hands off her, she's mine!
Oh my!
What are these filthy-minded Krauts been saying, sweetheart?
Come on, shutzy, throw a little my way.
You know, she looks a lot like the first one I ever had.
Olga.
Olga, my little peasant calf.
Come on, you never had anything like that.
Oh no?
See you later.
- Where are you going?- Sightseeing.
What's wrong with this sight?
(Inhales sharply)
(Both laughing)
我需要用6个星期才能把皮肤洗出来
It'll take six weeks to get to the skin!
-我能用用你那块香皂吗？-当然可以。-水怎么样？
- Can I have a piece of that soap?- How's the water?
好极了！赶紧下来吧，伙计
Beautiful! Come on in!
唉！快看呐
Hey! Look at that!
(All shout in mock French)
嗨！姑娘们，你们好
- Hello! Bonjour, bonjour!- Jolies! Jolies!
跟她们说点什么，叫她们过来
Somebody do something!Just don't let them get away!
哎，姑娘们过来
Allo, Mademoiselles!Allo, Mademoiselles!
姑娘们，过来吧
Ami! Ami, mademoiselles!
过来吧，姑娘们
Une minute, madame!
告诉她们别走啊
- Attendez, s'il vous plait!- Tell them to come over.
嗨，别走啊姑娘们，过来聊一聊好吗
Er, yes, er... Mademoiselle,You come over this side, oui?
我给你们爱情
Vous venez, s'il vous plaît.
-问她们今天晚上能做些什么？-姑娘们别走啊
- Ask them what they're doing tonight.- Don't let them get away!
姑娘们，别走好吗
Er, nous vivons à vous parler,all right?
(Girls giggling)
（以下一通乱喊，直到她们看到面包）
- Tell 'em we want to talk.- Talk?!
- Parlez vous, Mesdemoiselles!- Hey! Hey, wait a minute!
Tell them... Mademoiselles!
Venez assi!
No, that's not it, it's venez ici.
Frauleins, l'amour, yes?
You coming over,we have l'amour, yes?
Oui, oui, oui.
-不要走嘛！-呦吼吼！
- Don't go!- Yoo-hoo!
姑娘们！我这儿有面包，你们要面包吗？
Girls! Fraulein, bread, yes?You want bread?
看呐，姑娘们
Look! Regardez!
哞……，怎么样？面包
Yum-yum-yum-yum-yum, yes? Bread!
面包，啊，要吗？
You come over here, oui?
你们…
Vous!
今天晚上…
Venez!
到这儿来！
Ici!
Maintenant!
Oui! Oui!
-她们说些什么？-
- What did she say?- They want us to come over. No...
- Pas possible!- No, we can't!
We can't! There's guards, sentries,you understand? Watch.
We can't, they're up there.
(Whispering)
你们
Ce soir!
你们晚上
Vous venez!
到那边儿
Lá-bas!
我们的家里去
Nôtre maison!
他们要我们今天晚上去找她们去
They want us to come to their house tonight!
对，顺便带些吃的东西，懂吗？
Oui! Avec quelque chose à manger, oui?
要让我们带吃的过去！我们就住那边儿！
- (Paul) With something to eat!- La maison là!
去我们家
Maison!
姑娘们，再见！
- Bonjour! Bonjour! Bonjour!- Bye! Bye!
(Excited cheering)
全喝了，夏登
Drink up, Tjaden.
真够不走运的，她们是3个人，可是我们是4个
It's bad luck there's four of us and three of them.
哦，不走运
(Slurs) Mm-hmm... Bad luck.
我说我觉得这对姑娘不公平
See, I just don't think it's fair to the girls.
快喝干了吧夏登，难得有法国的好酒喝
Drink up, Tjaden. How often do you get good French wine?
为姑娘们…干杯
Not fair to the girls... No.
我们当中需要有人做出…巨大的牺牲
One of us will have to make the supreme sacrifice.
(⊙o⊙)嗯
Mmm?
干了吧夏登，你不用跟我们一起去了
Bottoms up, Tjaden,you're not keeping up with us.
(Mumbles)
要不我们抓阄吧？
Maybe we should draw lots?
你输了
You lose.
(Snoring)
来了，他们来了…快点儿披上，别着凉了，快上来，快上来…
(Chatter and laughter)
-晚上好。-晚上好
- Bonsoir.- (Girls) Bonsoir.
(Girls chuckle)
喔，有奶油，有面包，真是太好了，给你奶酪，你的
(Shout excitedly in French)
都坐下，大家都坐下，你自己先吃吗？给我，给我
(Chatter happily in French)
-很久没有吃到这么好吃的东西了。
-他们的面包也很好吃，要不要尝一块儿？
(Speaking French)
男：我觉得右边这个不错。女：这个很好吃，尝尝这个
This looks like the right line-up, huh?
男：我就要她了。女：（食物的味道）真不错
I'm all for this one.
你想做什么
You like yours, Albert?
哦，是的是的
Yes.
男：保罗？女：别急。瞧他们冻得！待会儿，肯定跟咱们上床了。
Paul?
你的脸色这么苍白？
Mais tu es blanc comme neige, toi.
哦…我…
Er...
我说的不对吗小家伙？
Est-ce que je me trompe,petit bon homme?
男：哦，是的是的。女：瞧他笑得多可爱
Oui!
(Clock chimes)
我的小战士
Mon petit soldat.
过来，过来
Viens. Viens.
来，坐这儿来
Non, non. Ici.
-你有多大了？-啊？
- Quelle âge as tu?- Eh?
-你多大了？
- Ton âge?- No...
-你的年龄？-哦，19
- Quelle âge as tu?- Ah! I'm nineteen.
Nineteen.
Nineteen... Oh!
25？我不信，你看上去没那么大
Vingt-cinq ans? Vraiment?Tu exaggeres, non?
The room grows dim and dissolves in the half-light
and only the face near mine lives and is clear.
The face is touched with a tenderness that comes out of the night...
and l let it all fall from me.
War and terror,
and grossness,
in order to awaken young and happy.
快隐蔽，快隐蔽
(Man) Look out! Look out! Take cover!
(Shouting and screaming)
(Panicked shouting)
快！快
Come on! Come on, Albert!
-我的腿！-快起来，快起来
- My leg!- Come on, Albert! Up! Up!
快！拉住我，快离开这儿
Come on, boys, a little bit more.
(Screams of agony)
趴下，趴下！
Down! Stay down!
(Shell whistles)
(Groaning)
我马上就回来
I'll be right back!
担架！
Hey!
(Screaming)
快，快！
Easy!
保罗
Paul!
你多保重
Take care!
你的枪，凯特
Kat.
凯特
Kat!
这边儿，走这边儿
Kat, come on!
-你会好的。-轻点儿
- All right.- Easy, easy.
-这是凯特给你的。-什么？
- It's from Kat.- What is it?
-路很远，你会饿的。-哦，面包和奶酪
- We got a long ride. You could get hungry.- Oh, bread and cheese!
是的，是面包和奶酪
啊，凯特，他可以从沙漠中找出一顿晚餐来
He could find a lobster dinner in the middle of the desert!
谢谢
Goodbye.
-再见。-谢谢
- Take care, Paul.- Bye.
(Whistle blows)
画外音：阿尔伯特和我住进了教堂医院
Albert and l are in a Catholic hospital.
我们真是有运气，教堂原是以良好的治疗和食物闻名遐迩
This is a piece of luck because Catholic infirmaries are noted
良好的治疗和食物闻名遐迩
for their good treatment and good food.
在上火车之前，我们一直坐卡车，我们两个人谁也没有睡好
We were wheeled in the night before and none of us slept well.
-再也见不到他了。-为什么？
- Won't see him again.- Why not?
他们拿走他的衣服，说明他去死亡屋了
They've taken his clothes.That means he's off to the Dead Room.
“死亡屋”什么意思？
The "Dead Room"?
什么死亡屋？
What's the Dead Room?
是个等死的地方，叫什么都一样
The Dying Room,whatever you wanna call it.
它是地下室中的一间小屋
It's in the basement.
只要有人想去那儿，想告别人间和生命
Whenever anybody wants to say "goodbye, life", they take 'em there.
就送他去，那的确很方便，它离太平间很近
It's convenient really.It's next to the mortuary.
没人从那儿走回来
No one ever comes back from it.
画外音：病床空得很快，新的病人又住了进来
The beds empty quickIy and new occupants take their places.
阿尔伯特的情况很不妙，他十分的痛苦
lt is going badly with Albert.He is in much pain.
昨天晚上，我们的一个病友从大失血中醒来
Last night one of our wardmates awakened with a severe haemorrhage.
他今天处于半昏迷状态，医生们更加频繁地进出了
He is only semi-conscious today.The doctors look in more often.
不要动我，不要！不要动我！
(Man) They won't take me! No! No!
这是送你去换药室
(Nurse) We're taking you to the bandaging room.
我不要去死亡屋，我要待在这儿，待在这儿
I won't go to the Dying Room!Stay here! Stay here!
我们送你去换药室
(Nurse) We're going to the bandaging ward.
那你为什么拿他的上衣？
Then why are you taking his tunic?
-我要待在这儿！-那你为什么拿他的上衣？
- I'll be back. I won't die!- Why are you taking his tunic?
我要待在这儿
(Man) I'll come back!I won't die! I'll come back!
留下他
Liars!
你们撒谎
They're lying.
留下
Liars!
我不想死
(Man) I'll come back!I'll come back! I won't die...
l am learning to walk again but always in the corridor.
l can't bear Albert's gaze if l move abut the room.
He has a strange look. l know what it is because l know Albert.
He is bitter and jealous that l am getting better and he is not.
And l know he has a terrible guilt that he feeIs jeaIous of me.
l know Albert.
He's always been my best friend.
l get to know this hospital very well,
where they keep the abdonimal
and spinaI cases,
the head wounds and double amputations,
the jaw wounds, the tesictle wounds,
the gas cases,
the blind cases,
the lung wounds and intestinal wounds.
And this is only one hospital.One singIe station.
There are thousands in Germany.
How many thousands are there in France?
ln Russia?
ln England?
How senseless is everything that can ever be written, done and thought,
when such things are possible?
The culture of a thousand years could not prevent this stream of blood
being poured out.
A hospital alone shows what war is.
(Banging and sobbing)
住手
Stop it!
你快住手
Stop it! Stop that! Orderly!
你快住手！医生！
Get the orderly! Doctor!
医生快来！
Orderly! Orderly!
他想自杀
He's trying to kill himself with a fork!
(Hysterical sobbing)
你干嘛要阻止他？
Why didn't you leave him alone?
你恢复得真好，保罗
You are doing so well, Paul.
不久就不用拐杖了
Soon we'll throw away the cane.
-小姐，-什么事？
- Sister.- Yes?
我很为我的朋友担心
I'm worried about my friend.
我想…他正在慢慢顺利地恢复
I think...he is making a very good recovery.
他让我担心
He worries me.
手术以后，他…
Since the operation, he...
他神智十分的模糊，甚至不能同我讲话了
He's in a terrible state of mind.He hardly speaks to me any more.
一般情况下，截肢手术以后，常有这种情况
There is always such a reaction after an amputation.
常有的
Always!
现在，别再担心了
Now, stop worrying.
阿尔伯特会好起来的
Albert will get over it.
去吧，把你的好消息告诉他
Go, tell him your good news.
会让他振奋的
That should cheer him up.
阿尔伯特
Albert?
你怎么样
How do you feel?
阿尔伯特，他们给了我16天的疗养假期
Albert, they're giving me 16 days' convalescent leave.
我打算回家一趟
I'll be going home.
他们也会送你回家的
They'll be sending you home, too.Very soon.
Baumer! Hey, Baumer.It's me, I'm back.
- Franz!
- Didn't I tell you I'd come back?
- I don't believe it.
- Death Room, Dying Room.
(Coughs) What the...hell
are they talking about?
Old Man Death didn't catch me.
I caught him out! (Coughs)
He did say he'd come back.
Didn't he?
阿尔伯特，我能帮你做点儿什么吗？
Albert, is there anything I can get you?
我要把枪
A gun.
什么？
A what?
你不是想帮我吗？给我把枪吧
You want to get me something?Get me a gun.
-你能不能给我一把枪？-别这样，不要胡说阿尔伯特
- Are you going to get me a gun or not?- No! Don't talk nonsense!
不，是你在胡说
No, you talk sense.
阿尔伯特
Albert...
对不起
I'm sorry.
(Baby crying)
保罗？
Paul?
保罗，你怎么不告诉我们你要回来？
Paul! Why didn't you tell us you were coming?
妈妈，妈妈
Mother. Mother!
(Sobs)
保罗，上来呀
Paul? Come up.
把手绢给我用用
Give me your handkerchief.
妈妈怎么样？
How is she?
噢，她病了
She's in bed.
她在床上，保罗
She's sick, Paul.
什么病？
What is it?
还不清楚
We don't know.
可…布莱顿医生说…这回是癌症
But...Dr Bradermeier thinks...it's probably the cancer again.
噢，感谢上帝
(Mother) Thank God.
哦，感谢…
Oh, thank God.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
你受伤了吧，保罗？
Are you wounded, Paul?
没有…我没有受伤，我是请假回来的
No... No, I'm just on leave.
-啊…-您身体好吗？
- Oh, Paul.- How are you feeling?
我今天大概都能坐起来了，还行吧
I'm going to try to get up a little today, I think.
很好
Good.
They must have known you were coming.
Ernst is making your favourite potato cakes.
And there's a bottle of whortleberryjam with them.
- You like that, don't you?- Yes, I haven't had any for a long time.
Where's Father?
At the sulphur factory.
He's working overtime.
我的孩子，我的保罗
My Paul.
您看
Look.
面包
Bread.
奶酪…黄油
And cheese and...butter!
有断顿的时候吗，孩子？
They feed you enough where you are?
不是很经常，但是我们会有办法的
Not always enough, but we manage.
前线很糟？
Is it very bad there?
不
No.
不是很糟
Not so bad.
海因里希·布莱顿医生来过
Heinrich Bradermeier was here
他说前线那儿很糟，他们放毒气
and said it's terrible out there,with the gas attacks
还有别的武器
and all the rest of it.
这些都是传说妈妈
It's just talk.
只是传说
Just talk.
你看我，挺好的是吗？
Look at me, I'm well and fit,aren't I?
是的
Yes.
那就好
But then...
我始终不理解你为什么要脱去军装
I still don't understand why you want to take off your uniform.
这样只是略微舒服一些，爸爸。没什么
It's just more comfortable,Father, that's all.
可是…可我还准备向别人夸耀说
But I...I want to show off our soldier boy
我有个当兵的儿子
to the fellows at Max's.
你气色不错，保罗，战争很适合你啊，嗯？
You look well, Paul. Fit.War agrees with you, eh?
也许是吧，哲尔先生
I suppose, in a way.
-来支雪茄吧。-哦不，谢谢
- Have a cigar.- No, thank you.
你这年龄都能杀法国人了，抽支烟还算什么
If you're old enough to kill Frenchmen,you're old enough to smoke.
汉斯，给年轻的战士来杯啤酒
Hans, another beer for our young warrior.
前线的士气怎么样？非常高昂吗，啊？
What's the spirit like out there?Excellent, eh?
我想要做的是，把法国人全都收拾了
I can believe it. The thing to do now is finish off the Froggies.
敌人有很强的战斗力，霍勒斯坦先生
The enemy has many reserves,Mr Hollerstein.
这场战争和人们想的有点儿不太一样
The war may be different from what people think.
你只说对了一半儿，保罗
You only see your little sector,
你只看到了一部分，有时候你忽略了对全局的把握
sometimes you lose sight of the large picture.
我认为你应当突破它们。这是弗兰德斯
The important thing as I see it is the breakthrough, here in Flanders.
这是法国人；还有这个呢，是我们
This is Frenchie, this is us.
我们应该从比利时一侧绕过去突破它们的防线
We have to come round the Belgian side and ram through.
此外，别无选择
There's no other way.
在辛德堡防线不先打败它们，你怎么绕过去？
How can we do that before we beat them on the Hindenburg line?
国界在战争中最为重要
It is borders that are important.
你完全错了，鲍勃。
一个优秀的士兵决不能像萝卜那样待在国界上
You're quite wrong.
A good soldier never stays planted on a border like a turnip.
-他要前进。-我赞成路德维柯
- He advances.- I agree with Ludwig.
进攻是现代战争的灵魂，看看1870年的战争吧
Offence is the key to modern warfare.Look what happened in 1870.
胡说，哲尔。我们在讨论现代战争，而不是50年前的事情
Nonsense. We're talking about modern warfare, not what happened 50 years ago.
你没讲实话，保罗，我知道你在说谎
You're lying to me, Paul.I know that you are.
我发誓，他当时就死了
I swear to you, he died instantly.
-你保证说，他不会受伤的。-堪布里希，我当时什么也…
- You promised me he wouldn't get hurt.- Mrs Kemmerich, I...
他死了为什么你还活着？为什么？
Why are you living when he is dead? Why?
你有什么权利
What right have you?
再说一遍
Tell me again.
你看到他死了？
Did you...see it?
是的，我当时就在他身边
Yes, I was right there next to him.
他死得很快，毫无痛苦
He died at once. He never suffered.
我知道你想要安慰我
I know that you're trying to comfort me,
但这样更让人痛苦，比讲实话还痛苦
but don't you see it is harder this way than if you told the truth?
我要知道事情真相
I want to know the...
我要真相
(Sobbing) I want the truth!
我要亲耳听到
I have to hear it!
堪布里希夫人，我发誓，我说的全部是事实
Mrs Kemmerich, I promise you,that's exactly how it happened.
他但是就死了，什么痛苦的感觉也没有
He died immediately.He felt absolutely nothing at all.
他的表情十分的平静
His face was quite calm.
-你发誓吗？-是的
- Do you swear it?- Yes.
为1000多的人发誓？
By everything that is sacred to you?
为异国的全部的人发誓
By everything that is sacred to me.
他当时就死了
He died at once.
如果这不是真的，你发誓不再回来了
And do you promise never to come back...if it is not true?
如果我说了谎
May I never come back...
我就再也不回来了
if he wasn't killed instantly.
把你们学到的带到前线去
Carry that lesson to the front lines
你们将成为优秀的士兵，为皇帝战斗
and you will be better soldiers in the service of the Kaiser.
现在下课
You are dismissed.
鲍曼
Baumer.
保罗·鲍曼
Paul Baumer!
鲍曼
Baumer!
-来支香烟吧。-不，谢谢
- Here, have a cigarette.- No, thank you.
瞧你还没改掉这个习惯，这很好，这不是什么好习惯
You still haven't picked up the habit.Well, that's good.
人总是有些坏毛病的吧？啊？
It's not a good habit but a man has to have some vices.
你还是只有工作，没有娱乐…还记得吗？
How does it go? All work and no play... You remember?
是的
(Coughs) Yes...
我说，怎么样？鲍曼？士气，士气怎么样？鲍曼？
How is it, Baumer?How...how is the spirit?
士气，士气很高昂，是吧？
Excellent, eh? Excellent?
贝母死了
Behm is dead.
贝母？
Behm?
约瑟夫·贝母
Josef Behm.
哦，你知道，我认为他不该入伍
Oh. You know,I didn't think he would enlist.
可他去了
But he went.
是啊
Yes...
堪布里希也死了
Kemmerich is dead, too.
啊，有人告诉我了
I was told.
还有克洛普丢了一条腿
And Kropp has lost a leg.
哦……噢，阿尔伯特·克洛普
Er... Oh, Albert Kropp, yes.
其他人我不太清楚，我们很早就分开了。不过里尔还在
I don't know about all the others.We were separated, but Leer's alive
缪勒活着，我们也活着
and Müller is alive and I'm alive.
真让人高兴
I'm glad to hear that.
告诉他们
(Chuckles) Tell them...
转告他们我很自豪，把他们培养成为优秀的德国人
Tell them I'm proud to have taught them to be good Germans.
我为你们为祖国付出的一切而感到自豪
To know that you have all done your duty by the Fatherland.
你能想象到我有多高兴
Can you imagine how that makes me feel?
你们这个班很好，都是好孩子
You were a good class. Good boys.
祖国的优秀儿女
Good boys all.
-现在这个班呢？-哼，这个班？
- And this class?- This lot? (Laughs)
不一样。失败主义传染了他们
Not like you. Defeatism,it has infected them.
他们没你们的精神，鲍曼
They haven't got your spirit, Baumer.
不再是坚强的青年了，嗯？
Not the Iron Youth, eh?
什么？嗯？
Mm? I'm sorry...?
你的坚强青年
No Iron Heroes?
他们只是孩子
Just boys.
还要玩耍
Want to play.
嬉笑
Laugh.
想活着
To stay alive.
他们还只是孩子
Only boys.
(Footsteps outside)
妈妈，很晚了，你该去睡觉了
Mother, it's late.You should be asleep.
想和你多待一会儿，对不起
Did I wake you, dear? I'm sorry.
你要着凉的，去睡吧妈妈
You'll catch cold here. Go, sleep.
我实在睡不着
I can sleep enough later.
你在那边害怕吗？
Are you very much afraid?
不
No.
我想提醒你，你一定要时刻提防一些法国女人
I'd like to tell you to be on your guard against the women in France.
他们没有那么好
They're no good.
妈妈，在我们那里，一个女人也没有
Mother, where we are there aren't any women.
在前线一定要小心呐保罗
And be very careful at the front, Paul.
-是的，一定。-我每天都在为你祈祷
- Yes, I will.- I pray for you every day.
我知道，妈妈
I know, Mother.
也许，你可以找到一份安稳的事情做
Perhaps you can get a job that is not so dangerous?
是，也许我应该去炊事班，这很容易做到，妈妈
Yes, perhaps in the cookhouse.That could be easily done.
那你就去吧，如果别人说起…
You do it, then,and if the others say anything...
我不怕别人说什么
I won't let that bother me.
现在，您应该去睡觉了，妈妈。去吧，来
Now, you must go to sleep, Mother.Come on.
You must get well, Mother,before I come home.
Yes, my child.
And you must not send any more things to me.
We get plenty to eat out there.
You can make much better use of them here.
Oh, I have two pair of underpants for you.
All wool.
They will keep you warm.
You must not forget to put them in your bag.
I won't, Mother.
Good night.
My son.
妈妈，我过去一直住在这屋里，我的一切都在这儿
Mother, l used to live in this room.All my things are here.
所有的书，所有我珍爱的书
All my books, my beloved books,
可是他们不再像从前那样对我诉说了
but they no longer speak to me as they used to,
因为现在的我已经不是当时住在这里的我了
for l am not what l was when l lived in this room.
我现在是士兵，我的事业不再是读书，而是杀戮
l am a soldier. My business is not reading, it is killing.
我对生命的知识仅限于死
My knowledge of life is limited to death,
我知道，我不该再回来
and l know now l should never have come back.
外面的人们和我一样想
Out there, all men think as l do.
没有必要争论生命的意义
There's no argument about the meaning of life,
因为它本无意义
because it has no meaning.
我只知道我的同伴正在前线
My companions at the front are the only truth l know.
他们不是我的书籍、家庭和生命
They are now my books,my family, my life.
但我需要他们，我不再需要别的什么
l depend on them and l depend on nothing else.
妈妈，说这些话很可怕
Mother, it's a terrible thing to say,
但我感觉我现在该去找我真正的归宿了
but l feel l am now going back to my reaI home.
-保罗。-快快，快下车
(Kat) Paul!
-好啊，你回来了。-是的，我回来了
- Well, you're back, my boy.- Yes, I'm back.
傻瓜才不回来呢，回来我很高兴，保罗
You're a fool for coming back.I'm glad to see you, anyway.
我也很高兴，凯特
I'm glad to see you, too, Kat.
他们送来了更加年轻的
They're getting younger and younger, Paul.
光照顾他们就够咱们受的
Our hands'll be full just taking care of them.
嗨！啊～～老逃兵回来啦
Hey! The old deserter's back!
(Welcoming shouts)
-嘿，保罗，你好啊？-很好，缪勒呢？
- How was your leave?- Good. Where's Müller?
-什么时候？-一周以前
- When was it?- A week ago.
死得快吗？
Was it quick?
弹片击中了他的腹部，躺了两个小时
Shrapnel in the stomach.He lasted two hours.
Paul...
He said I could have them.
(Gunfire and explosions)
混账
Damn!
等他们再近一点，我们先开火
If they come any closer,we're done for.
队长
Lieutenant!
-里尔！-别管他，他完了！快回来
(Paul) Leer! No, leave him!He's gone! He's gone!
回来！里尔
Leer! Come back!
里尔！
God!
噢，上帝呀！
Oh, God! God! God! God!
(Sobbing)
(Explosion and screams)
-冲啊！杀呀！-冲啊！
- Ready! Charge!- Let's go!
(Gunfire and explosions)
(Shouting and screaming)
画外音：我们给前线的战友们运送食物
We are bringing food to our comrades at the front.
前面食物紧缺，我们都饿得发慌，精疲力尽…
There isn't much. We are all going hungry. We are all tired.
一片茫然，然而，仗还在打
We are all hopeless.But the war goes on.
他们为什么不结束战争啊？
Why don't theyjust let it end?
哦，谁知道呢
Ah, who knows?
快完了
We're finished.
饿得要死，而法国人正在吃鲜牛肉和白面包
We're starving, and the Froggies are eating corned beef and white bread.
我们只有面包渣了，该死
Our bread is nothing but sawdust.
你看见有谁不得痢疾和肚子疼呢？
You see anybody that hasn't got dysentery and colic?
大炮被烧坏了
Artillery's burned out.
枪把‘儿又磨掉了…
Damned barrels are so worn down... Ha!
炮弹也飞不远了，炸死了我们自己的人
..the shells are falling short and half the time our men are being killed.
可是我们现在呢，没有一匹马。可是敌人呢，却越来越多
There's just too many of the enemy left.They've got too much.
他们太强大了，那么多的机枪、坦克，美国人也卷入战争
Too many guns, tanks.Now the Americans are pouring in.
新式机枪、飞机，兵员不断
New guns, aeroplanes, fresh troops.
(Shells whistling)
(Kat groans)
躺着别动
Lie still.
-眼看着要结束了，快要结束了！-别说话
- Just as it's ending!- Be quiet!
-4年过去了。-救护员！
- After four years.- Stretcher!
-救护员！-快要结束了
- Stretcher bearer!- Just as it's ending.
你会好的，别紧张
It's all right. Just lie still.
没关系，伤口不严重
Don't worry,it looks like a clean wound.
你只要坚持一会儿
If you can just hold on.
再坚持一会儿就躺在床上了，医院的床上
Before you know it you'll be in a comfortable bed in a hospital.
救护员！
Stretcher!
你能站起来吗？
Think you can stand up?
来吧，我们试试，来
Think you can get up?
走，我们走
Come on. Come on! Come on!
不行。来吧，我背你走
I've got to carry you.
我们走
Ready? Up.
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系，保罗，没关系
That's all right, Paul. That's all right.
我们得赶紧走，你能行吗？
We gotta keep going. You ready?
是的，我能行
Yes, yes.
我们走
Come on.
-行吗？-我试试
- You got it?- I'll try.
-我试试，-算了凯特，我背你走
- No.- No, I'll try.
来吧，我们走
No, you can't. It's all right.
(Shells whistling)
- What is it?- My pipe.
I think I've lost my pipe.
Don't worry.
We'll find another one.
- Here.- (Loud explosion)
Well, Kat...
I think we're gonna be separated.
Three years.
You remember when I first came up here?
How green I was?
You fixed that. "Keep your head down."
That's what you said.
Maybe... Maybe, when this is over,
when this war is really finished,
maybe we can do something together. Huh?
- (Explosion)- I don't know what.
Glass of wine.
I don't even know where you live.
Three years in the same trenches,I don't even have your address.
Let me give you mine. Let me give it to you.
Let's...
Let's go on.
- Come on. Ready?- Yeah.
Come on!
(Straining)
(Shells whistling)
你早该放下他了，他已经僵死了
(Doctor) You might have spared yourself. Stone dead.
不
No.
他伤了小腿，只是昏迷
It's his shin, he's fainted.
来吧凯特，醒醒！
Come on, Kat, come on.
他一直在说话
He was talking.
10分钟以前
Ten minutes ago.
我们…还在说话
We were talking.
画外音：秋天来了，我们盼望着结束
lt is autumn.We wait for the end.
我们等待着休战
We wait for the Armistice.
渴望着和平
We wait for peace.
亲爱的阿尔伯特，我写信告诉你说，我俩是幸存的人了
Dear Albert, l write to tell you you and l are the last ones left.
凯特死后不久，夏登也死了，他死得迅速而幸福
Soon after Kat died, Tjaden got it a quick and merciful death,
子弹穿过脑颅
a bullet in the head.
西摩尔斯托斯死于同一天
Himmelstoss was killed the same day
现在，德特林也不在了
and now Detering is gone.
好像去年春天起，德特林就不知道去哪儿了
l think we started to lose Detering last spring,
那正是苹果花盛开的时候
when the apple trees came into bloom.
你知道，这是他描述春天的词句
You know that expression of his in springtime?
两星期前点名时想起了他，哪儿都没有他
Two weeks ago he was missed at roll-call, nowhere to be found.
一周后，我们听说他被宪兵找到了
A week later we heard he had been caught by the MiIitary PoIice.
你我都清楚会在哪里。在家里，收获的地方
You and l know where he was going.Home, to the harvest.
此后就再也没有他的消息了，你知道逃兵会有什么下场
We have not heard anything more,but you know the penalty for desertion.
阿尔伯特，我们1916班
Albert, of the class of 1916,
总共20名报名参军的人，13名死去了
out of the 20 who enlisted,13 are dead.
4个人失踪
Four are missing.
1个在疯人院
One is in a madhouse.
只有你和我还活着
You and l live.
我是多么的想念你呀
How I miss you.
(Gunshot)
(Bird sings)
(Birdsong continues)